Finding aid to the Smith College Club of North Shore records CA.MS.00310
Smith College Archives
Smith College Club of North Shore records
1920-2007
Smith College Archives
Smith Club of North Shore
CA.MS.00310
1.042 linear feet (2 containers)
The Smith College Club of North Shore formed as a fusion between the Lynn Smith Club (founded 1917) and the Salem Smith Club (founded 1919), at the suggestion of the Alumnae Association, in 1934. Its records contain minutes, annual meeting reports, membership directories, event fliers, newspaper clippings, and correspondence of the Smith College Club of North Shore.
Biographical / Historical
The Smith College Club of North Shore formed as a fusion between the Lynn Smith Club (founded 1917) and the Salem Smith Club (founded 1919), at the suggestion of the Alumnae Association, in 1934. The early meetings of the groups were social and informal. The Smith Club of North Shore's ongoing Autumn Supper is its longstanding tradition, started in 1948. The supper provides a meal for both alumnae and prospective students, and is the first event in the Club's active year. Annual fundraising events include Macadamia for Academia, begun in 1970, which is the Smith College Club of North Shore's spinoff of pecan sales. They also sell S'mints, begun in 1992, which are chocolates with a Grecourt Gate design. Notable Smith alumnae have participated in events for the Smith College Club of North Shore, such as Julia McWilliams Child (1934), who gave a lecture in 1990.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains meeting minutes from the 1920s to the late 2000s, annual reports, and documentation of many of the club's events through fliers and newspaper clippings. Most of the material is administrative and reflects minutes of club committees, changes in by-laws, and reports of different meetings and events. Additional materials are plays performed by the Lynn Smith Club at alumnae events during the 1930s, as well as Smith College publications about alumnae clubs and the college.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Smith College Club of North Shore records were donated over a period of time to the Smith College Archives from a variety of sources.
- Club history, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Club history, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Club history, 1976-1988 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- By-laws, 1954-1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Executive Board minutes notebook (disassembled), 1951-1956 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Executive Board minutes notebook, 1956-1963 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Executive Board minutes, 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Executive Board minutes, 1967-1977 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Executive Board minutes, 1977-1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Board meeting agendas, 1987-1995 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Board meeting agendas, 1995-2001 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Board minutes, 1965-1972 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Board minutes, 1972-1978 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Board minutes, 1979-1987 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Board minutes, 1987-1995 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Annual reports, 1928-1959 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Annual reports, 1963-1970 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Annual reports, 1971-1975 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Annual reports, 1975-1979 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Annual reports, 1979-1983 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Annual reports, 1983-1987 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Annual reports, 1987-1991 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Annual reports, 1992-1995 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Annual reports, 1996-2007 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Annual meeting minutes, 1964-1984 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Annual meeting minutes, 1984-2007 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Annual meeting flyers, 1975-2001 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Reports from Alumnae Council, 1984-1989 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Reports from Alumnae Admissions Committee, 1998-2004 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Reports from Nominating Committee, 1968-1974 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Club minutes notebook, 1920-1929 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Club minutes, 1963-1966 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Club minutes, 1966-1970 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Club minutes, 1971-1977 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Club minutes, 1977-1991 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Treasurers' reports, 1968-2004 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Financial documents, undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Fundraising, 1968-1993 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Fundraising, undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Photo: Lynn Smith Club, rummage sale to benefit scholarship fund, ca. 1930s (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Officers and directors, 1963-1993 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Officers and directors, 1995-2005 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Membership lists, 1955-2007 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Membership, 1959-1972 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Membership, 1972-1988 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Membership, 1988-1999 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Membership, 2000-2003 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Correspondence, 1931-1976 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Correspondence, 1978-1991 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Correspondence, 1992-1995 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Correspondence, 1996-1998 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Correspondence, 1998-2007 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Events, 1933-1977 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Events, 1978-1989 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Events, 1990-1994 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Events, 1994-2003 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Events, 2004-2007 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Events: Club calendars, 1974-1995 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Newsletters, 1990-2007 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Clippings, 1935-2002 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Play scripts, 1935-1937 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Notebook of Alumnae College attendee, Josephine Esselen (1938), 1985-1993 (Box 2, Folder 10)